<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marine Data Science</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marine Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 - present [Saskia Otto](https://github.com/saskiaotto)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R code test</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/17/r-code-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/17/r-code-test/</guid>
      <description>Test how R code looks like This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing indicator performance</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/16/testing-indicator-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/16/testing-indicator-performance/</guid>
      <description>Indicators are useful and versatile tools applied in disciplines such as engineering, chemistry, medicine, economy or sociology. In ecosystem-based management a key role of an indicator is to inform on the current status of the system component as well as the effectiveness of specific management measures to move the component into a different state. In European Union (EU) marine policy, indicator development has recently progressed as part of the implementation of the Marine Strategy Framework Directive (MSFD) to aid the achievement of Good Environmental Status (GES) of the EU’s marine waters by 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a postdoctoral researcher and lecturer at the Institute of Marine Ecosystem and Fishery Science (formerly known as Institute for Hydrobiology and Fisheries Sciences). I have been working in the field of marine and freshwater ecology since my academic studies as researcher or consultant with a broad focus ranging from fish ecophysiology, diversity of marine temperate fouling communities, management of coral reefs and impacts of heavy metal pollution in the tropics to temperate freshwater fish communities and brackish pelagic food webs in recent years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Any comments or questions? Are you curious about something? Do you have any questions? Let me know and I will try to answer them. If you have any information on interesting data bases or R packages I should add to the list, let me know. And if you have any tutorial or online course related to MDS that you would like to share through this platform you are more then welcome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databases &amp; Data Packages</title>
      <link>/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data/</guid>
      <description>Databases In the following you find a list of databases and repositories that provide different type of marine data for specific regions free of charge. The list is not intended to be exhaustive but more to give you an easy start and many of these database can be webscraped directly from within R using specific packages that I also list here. If you feel there is any global or regional database missing where users can download marine data, don’t hesitate to contact me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marine Data Science</title>
      <link>/mds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mds/</guid>
      <description>What is Marine Data Science (MDS)? MDS is all about uncovering findings from marine data such as oceanographical data collected using both in situ methods and remote sensing. Typical parameters measured on-board relate to near-surface meteorological conditions (air temperature, wind speed, wind direction, cloudiness, etc.), sea surface conditions (e.g. sea surface temperature (SST), salinity, wave height, and wave direction) as well as subsurface water characteristics (vertical profiles of temperature, salinity, dissolved nutrients, ocean currents, or ocean bottom depth).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Courses &amp; Tutorials</title>
      <link>/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/</guid>
      <description>In addition to the blog tutorials you here find a list of external courses and tutorials on marine data science taught by me (on https://github.com/mareds) or colleagues.
General Courses Data Analysis With R: This is a course taught by me as part of the curriculum of the Master program MARSYS at the Institute of Marine Ecosystem and Fishery Science, University of Hamburg, Germany. The course can be used as a short-term (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/</guid>
      <description>Which programming languages should you learn for marine data science? First of all, there is no easy answer and no consensus either. Choosing from the broad range of programming languages the right one to invest time and effort learning it the next month or years is not trivial. It all boils down to what you plan to do with it and whether you want an open source program or can afford a license.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>